https://maas.museum/privacy/

Update: The Powerhouse Museum, Sydney Observatory and Museums Discovery Centre are now open. Read more
The Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences acknowledges Australia’s First Nations Peoples as the Traditional Owners and Custodians of the land and gives respect to the Elders – past and present – and through them to all Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander peoples.
Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander peoples are advised that the MAAS website contains a range of material which may be culturally sensitive including records of people who may have passed away.
Next
Continue
Privacy
Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences is committed to protecting your privacy, including throughout and as a result of your interaction/s with our websites. These include:
maas.museum
collection.maas.museum
sydneyscience.com.au
sydneydesign.com.au
api.maas.museum
new.maas.museum
archive.maas.museum
museumex.maas.museum
labs.maas.museum
ma.as
www.themarslab.org
www.australiandressregister.org
www.dhub.org
and all subsections of the above.
Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences is subject to the NSW Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act (1998). The Museum’s Privacy Management Plan outlines how the Museum complies with the Act.
Email newsletters
The Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences offers regular email bulletins. In sending email newsletters MAAS complies with the Australian Government’s Spam Act 2003. By signing up for an email newsletter you are explicitly giving consent to receive that newsletter at the regular interval specified at the time of signing up. All bulk emails have an opt-out feature in their footer and the secure email service MAAS utilises explicitly prevents resending to any addresses that have opted out. Email addresses attached to one list are never merged or added into other MAAS lists. All these lists are also covered by the NSW Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act (1998) and are never passed on to, traded or sold to third parties.
Automatic logging of information
(Internet Protocol) addresses [an IP is the address of a computer] of visitors are automatically logged by our servers. The server makes a record of your visit and logs limited information for statistical purposes – your IP address, top-level domain name (.com, .gov, .edu, com.au etc), the date and time of your visit to our site, pages accessed and documents downloaded, previous site visited and the type of browser used. These logs are used to administer the website and to diagnose problems in order to be able to rectify them. This data is also used for audience research to help us to improve the site.
IP addresses do not contain any personally identifiable information and are aggregated for analysis. Such aggregate data may be provided to internal departments only. Recording usage patterns helps us to identify popular areas of our site, and helps us to improve the site. Reports generated on aggregate data are periodically sent to State Government as part of the Museum’s statutory requirements.
Collection of personal information
Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences collects personal information such as name, phone number/email address/postal address when you provide it in order to receive specific Museum services. This information is stored in secure MAAS databases. The information you provide will be used solely by the relevant MAAS staff for its intended purpose, as stated on those pages. Your name, contact details and other information will not be provided to any other person or third-party organisation without your consent.
Your provision of personal details is optional, however some services may not be available to you if you do not provide these details.
If you contact MAAS via this website, your email address will be used only to reply to you – which may require it to be sent on to the appropriate staff member. Your email address will not be added to a mailing list or disclosed to any other person or organisation without your consent.
This website may use third party tracking and monitoring tools. These tools may record information about your user session but do not record personal information other than about your IP address, internet browser and search terms. If you wish to opt out of these tools then we would recommend disabling Javascript and turning off cookies. Please be aware that some areas of our website may not function correctly with these turned off.
Use of cookies
Cookies are small files that a website can store on a user’s computer and are used for keeping the ‘state of a user session’ i.e. remembering who you are from a page requesting information through to supplying it. The cookies that are used by the MAAS websites do not collect any personal information and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to tell us who you are other than to authenticate the user for security purposes.
We also use cookies to measure certain visitor patterns, including areas of the website you have visited. This research is used to help us understand user habits, so the website can be improved.
If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can adjust your internet browser to refuse cookies or to warn you when cookies are being used. Refusal may make some parts of our websites inaccessible, unusable, or not function correctly.
Use of pixels
Pixels are 1 x 1 pixel images that allow services to tell companies how many people have visited their site. When you take a certain action on our website, a request is sent to the server to download the tracking pixel attached to the content you’re interacting with. It’s an invisible process to you but the data collected will help us build better digital ad and content experiences for you. All information collected is de-identified and we will never collect or disclose any personal information.
Collection search data
Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences collection search and the collection search on Design Hub (dhub.org) anonymously stores all search terms to enable better ordering and sorting of search results, as well as for internal museum evaluation purposes. At no time are search results stored with any personally identifying information. The museum does not collect IP addresses against search terms in our collection databases.
Disclosure
Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences will not disclose your personal information to any third party except when required by law and/or in accordance with the Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act, 1998.
MAAS may be required to disclose your personal information to third parties to provide the service you requested. For example, in purchasing products online, we will need to disclose personal information to third parties in order to bill and deliver your products. This disclosure, however, will only be made to fulfil the purpose for which you disclosed your personal information. We will not disclose your personal information for any other purpose unless you have authorised us to do so.
External links
This site contains links to other sites. Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites.
Public forums and listservers
There are interactive features on some of the MAAS websites including email groups and online collaborative functionality. These services are opt-in services and by their nature require that certain details are transmitted to third parties. For example, a participatory email discussion list requires disclosure of email addresses to other participants in the group when you post messages for discussion. If you post personal information in publicly accessible online forums, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Please do not post any information that you do not want seen in these public areas.
Security
This site uses secure credit card facilities provided by two third party providers. Online book sales and memberships are handled securely by Westpac. Ticket sales are handled by Sabo and a range of other third party providers, as noted on individual pages and events. Please refer to their respective privacy and security policies for details on their services.
This site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control.
Contact details
If you have any questions about this Online Privacy Statement, please contact the Museum’s Privacy Officer by telephoning (02) 9217 0350.
